Nelma Perera

Email: npererar@gmail.com | GitHub: github.com/nelmiux | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/npererar

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a passionate technologist, driven by a desire to learn, improve myself, the team, and the products we deliver. I am full-stack software developer with extensive experience building enterprise level web/mobile applications and services.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

August 2018 – Present

Dell Technologies - Austin, TX

- Lead the design, implementation, and deployment of enterprise level scalable web applications and services over cloud native infrastructures.
- Share knowledge in performance, scalability, enterprise application architecture, DevOps, and best practices.

Technologies: .NET Core/C#, Spring/Java, JS, Typescript, Angular, Docker/CF containers, Swagger, Splunk, Git, PCF.

Application Development Analyst

October 2016 – August 2018

Travis County - Austin, TX

- TDD, Design and develop DDD RESTful data services APIs, inside containerized autonomous microservices to be distributed and load balanced through multiple servers.
- TDD, Design and develop MVC and SPA web and mobile applications on Angular 2+, ASP.NET Core, Android Studio, and Xcode.
- Write advanced queries and scripts to alert, extract, process, and correlate data events and logs using Splunk.
- Help DevOps with TFS definitions and Agile methodology implementation.

Technologies: C#, JS, Typescript, Angular, .NET standard, .NET Core, EF standard, EF Core, SQL, Docker containers, Swagger, Splunk, TFS.

CS Research Assistant

January 2016 – May 2016

University of Texas at Austin, TX

- Research and develop a software platform that allows automatic translation of SQL-to SPARQL over a Jena JDBC adapter.
- Develop a variety of web, iOS, and Android applications.

Technologies: Java, Python, Jena JDBC Driver, IntelliJ, Oracle SQL, RDF, SPARQL, Python, Django, UML, MySQL, Apiary, ElasticSearch, JS, Angular, Swift, Cocoa Touch, Xcode, Firebase, Java, Android SDK, Github.

CEO and Principal Software Developer

July 2008 – December 2012

Binarium Technology Corp. - Florida

- Responsible for all day-to-day management decisions, and software development.
- Advise customers regarding building and maintenance of diverse software systems.
- Lead and collaborate with team member to plan, design, and develop robust solutions.
- Exposure to a vast variety of technologies.

Technologies: C#, .NET, Java, Python, Django, PHP, JS, Objective-C, Android SDK, DevOps, TFS, Subversion.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science, University of Texas at Austin